

# Jan Füchtener Web Developer

### **About me**

I enjoy creating things that live on the internet, whether that be websites, applications, or anything in between. My goal is to always build products that provide pixel-perfect. performant experiences.

In my freetime you will probably find my in a yoga studio or playing handpan.

# Contact

- Zum Hoover Feld 13 50170 Kerpen Germany
- +49 1573 3145798
- jan@fuechtener.eu
- https://fuechtener.eu
- https://github.com/Fruchtix

### Skills

- ➤ React.js ➤ JavaScript (ES6+) ➤ HTML & CSS
- React Native Firebase Git
- ➤ Wordpress **➤** MySQL > Figma

### **Education**

2012 - 2017

#### Europagymnasium Kerpen

 Advanced courses in computer science and math

2017 - 2020

#### **Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.)**

- Information Science for Business (dt. Wirtschaftsinformatik) @FHDW
- Study Course specialisation: Software Engineering

# **Experience**

#### **CEO & Founder**



2019 - ongoing

Helped thousands of people to improve their eyesight and overcome lovesickness through my Apps EyeYoga and Breakup.

- Established companys in response to marketplace demand.
- Learned to design UI and to build projects from start to finish.

### Front End Developer (Freelance)



🗎 2020 - now

Worked for one of the biggest yoga retreats in spain (Suryalila) and supported a team of 8 people to organize an online yoga summit. I was responsible for the marketing and building the website as well as the actual livestreaming of the event.

# Software Engineer @nexible



**2019 - 2020** 

Wrote my bachelor thesis about the user authentication process within the nexible chatbot and programmed it afterwards. Also trained and improved the chatbot and learned more about machine learning.

# Software Engineer @Ergo



**2017 - 2019** 

Worked in a couple of different departments and looked into the processes behind a big insurance company. Got first hand experiences with Scrum and Kanban. Coded with COBOL, C# and used the Elastic Stack to analyse what websites employees are visiting.